MOHAMMAD ALI

Mob(Oman): +968-79567200

Mob(Bangladesh): +880-1792934063

E-Mail: hriday05@gmail.com

Link: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-ali-a560b452/

Professional Summary

Assertive and enthusiastic professional with 8 years of experience including extensive knowledge of Inventory, sales & operation planning , process optimization and an unsurpassed worth ethic. Ensuring profit margin, successfully reducing cost, streamline operation, enhance productivity and possesses excellent customer service.

Highlights

- Staff leadership & development
- Strategic planning
- Business Development
- B2B & B2C Sales
- Performance & Process improvement
- New Market identification

- Budget Control
- Supply chain and resource management
- Forecast & Demand Planning
- CRM & SRM
- Project Planning & Promotion
- Inventory planning & Control

Professional Experience

In charge- Inventory -Hino Spare parts-Saud Bahwan Automotive (Feb 2019-Present) Achievements

- Increased annual targeted sales more than 5% in 2019 by controlling cost & Maintaining inventory level for capital and four territory warehouse
- > Developed or implemented new procedures & systems
- Improved inventory turn over ratio & maximized profit

Key Responsibilities

- Implemented developed and maintained inventory planning & control policies and procedure
- Developed a monthly demand plan to support sales forecast
- Maintain positive work relationship with customers & principle HME,HMME to ensure smooth business Operation
- Analyzed inventory models & identified areas of saving for the organization
- Performed analysis to all weekly inventory movements to track margin and turnover
- Scheduled truck for efficient pick up & delivery to increase fill rate approximately 95%
- Recorded daily deliveries & shipment to maintain information required for periodic inventory Reconciliation
- Monitored demands and supply flow of over 15k line items to minimize back-orders and maximized fill rates
- Interfaced with cross-functional teams for ascertaining annual strategies, budgeting and planning funds for sourcing and procurement ensuring optimum utilization of material
- Handled Store Activities, key inventory task & monitored for inventory discrepancies ,reviewed existing inventory control practices & revised as necessary
- Processed claims, shortages, damaged goods, back orders, core returns, and overages
- ➤ Managed monthly S &OP processes, meetings and action plans, issue resolution and tracking

Territory In-charge, Hino Truck Spare Parts-Saud Bahwan Automotive (Dec 2012-Jan 2019)

Achievements

- Increased monthly targeted sale to approximately 10% at 2017 & 14% in 2018 through strong customer relationship and parts availability
- Awarded as best Territory in 2017 and 2018

Key Responsibilities

- Reviewed profitability of all lines to ensure high margin sales are maximized and low margin sales are reviewed to improved profitability
- Developed new business opportunity and expedite sales
- > Ensured all outstanding debts are collected in due time and customer queries or concerns are responded and resolved
- > Streamlining and standardizing the systems & procedures for effective inventory control and cycle time reduction to ensure availability of materials and increasing the inventory turnover
- Monitored demands and supply flow of over 2000 line items to minimize back-orders and maximized fill rates up to 95%
- > Improved SOP for territory inventory planning, bin location, Space optimization, Dispatch and received

Sr. Logistics Officer, Coats Bangladesh Ltd, Dhaka, Bangladesh (2011-2012)

Key Responsibilities

- Managed logistics operations, Store & procurement efficiently
- Monitored new warehouse PR & reduce cost.
- ➤ Reduced cost for locally procure items thru strong negotiation
- Followed the Supply Chain policy according to SC department as per compliance requirement to fulfill the business objectives & organizations goals

Education

- Rajshahi University of Engineering & Technology(RUET)- Rajshahi,Bangladesh
- Bachelor of Science in Industrial & Production Engineering (2006-2010)

Reference

Dr. Md. Mosharraf Hossain

HOD

Industrial & Production Engineering

(RUET) Rajshahi,Bangladesh. Phone: +088-(0721)750026

Fax: (0721)750026

Mobile: +88-01713-228545

E-mail: mosharraf80@yahoo.com

Rajesh Sharma

HOD

Hino truck Division

Saud Bahwan Automotive

Sultanate of Oman

Mobile:+968-99434896

Tel:+968-24527323

Fax-+968-24527333

E-mail: rajesh1402ind@gmail.com